Tiruppur, Tamil Nadu, India ☑ vinodeee093@gmail.com ☐ 9360641654 ☐ https://www.linkedin.com/in/vinodarumugam0407/

SUMMARY

Cloud Automation Tester experience in PySpark, ETL testing, Azure, and Python. Proven ability to design and execute test cases for data warehouse applications and cloud-based systems. Familiar with Agile/Scrum development methodology. Received Coral award from Associate Director for delivering project with good quality.

EXPERIENCE

Azure Cloud Data Tester

Cognizant Technology Solution -- Client: Blue Shield of California

May 2022 - Present, Coimbatore

- Automated the tests using data engineering pipeline which reduces 40% of testing effect.
- · Identified and addressed design gaps in the pipeline by business scenarios which increased 15% of pipeline efficiency.
- · Validated different types of files (parquet,csv,excel file) using pyspark and python automation scripts.
- · Enough Knowledge in Azure tools like Azure synapse analytics, Azure data factory and automated testing processes.

ETL Tester

Cognizant Technology Solution -- Client: Blue Shield of California

June 2021 - May 2022, Coimbatore

- Involved in writing complex SQL queries for Data Integrity checks which increases data accuracy by 60%.
- Created ETL Test Plans, Test Cases, Test Scenarios and Test Summary Reports based on project requirement.
- · Good Understanding in Test Management, ETL architecture and reporting tools like Jira, Hp ALM.
- Executed ETL validation scripts across target table to check transformation rules provided in data mapping sheet correctly implemented.
- · Logged defects and tracked defects using defect dashboards in Jira.

Internship -- Cognizant Technology Solution

Feb 2021- June 2021, Coimbatore

- · Created and Developed Automation Framework using selenium.
- · Worked in testing to run the script and used Xpath, locators, implicit wait in automation framework.
- · Experience in Java and SQL able to work on complex items.

PROJECTS

MDIF Enhanced

Blue Shield of California • May 2022 - Present

- Project aims to move to all database table and files from On-Premises server to Azure cloud using Azure Synapse.
- · Implemented Azure synapse concepts and automated the testing process for different types of source systems like files and databases.
- · Handled the team of 5 people and coordinated with the team members to deliver project on time.

AB929

Blue Shield of California • May 2021 - May 2022

- · Blue shield of California is a nonprofit health care organization providing Californians with high-quality of healthcare at an affordable price.
- Experience in healthcare concepts and terminologies like copay, coinsurance.
- Produced new business scenarios for testing which increases healthcare product quality by 30%.

CERTIFICATIONS

Azure Data Engineer

Microsoft • 2022

• Practical knowledge in Azure ADLS, Data Factory, Synapse, Apache spark and Data Warehouse.

Databricks Certified Data Engineer

Databricks • 2022

• Exposure to databricks platform and terminologies in databricks.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: Azure Data Factory, SQL, Data Lake, Unix, Informatica, Pyspark, Azure Synapse, Python, Datawarehouse, PostgreSQL, Jira, Jenkins.

Soft Skills: Teamwork, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Innovative, Communication, Time Management.

Languages: English, Tamil, Kannada

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Dr Mahalingam College of Engineering and Technology • Coimbatore • 2021 • 8.75